canso.org 2019-01-20

# CANSO Privacy Policy | CANSO

**This is the Privacy Policy of the Civil Air Navigation Services Organisation (CANSO) and CANSO B.V.**

CANSO, being a data controller established in the European Union, complies with the European Union's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Accordingly, for all processing activities we are required to inform you under which basis we collect, process, and use your personal data.

This Privacy Policy is to inform you about how your personal data is being used by our services online and offline. Personal data means any information relating to you that can be used to identify, contact, or locate you as an individual.  
As the voice of the global air traffic management community, we are committed to achieving the highest standards to protect your personal data and safeguard your privacy.

Please read our Privacy Policy carefully to have a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle personal data on all our services.

**Who are we and who to contact in case of concerns?**

This is the Privacy Policy of CANSO and its wholly-owned subsidiary CANSO B.V. Both entities are headquartered in the Netherlands.

You can contact us by e-mail at privacy@canso.org, by telephone at +31 (0)23 568 5380, or by post at CANSO, Transpolis Schiphol Airport, Polaris Avenue 85e, 2132 JH Hoofddorp, The Netherlands.

Should you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, wish to exercise your data subjects' rights, or have any concerns about our data collection practices, you can contact us.

Should you be unhappy with the way we are dealing with your personal details or the way we are addressing your concerns, please contact us and note that as a data subject you also have the right to refer a complaint to our supervisory authority, the Dutch Data Protection Authority: the Autoriteit Persoonsgevens which can be reached at www.autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl or with the supervisory authority in the country you are residing.

**What personal data do we process?**

CANSO processes personal data for a variety of purposes relating to our activities. We collect this personal data from our Members, existing and prospective customers, suppliers, stakeholders and staff.

We may collect, process, and use the following personal details for our services which includes but is not limited to: your name, gender, company, job title, nationality, birthdate, role and specialisation, contact details (including postal or email address, telephone number), credit card and financial information, photography and video recordings, curriculum vitae (also known as a resume), passport or identity card, and dietary requirements.

You can update and request a copy of your personal data listed at any time by getting in touch with CANSO via email at [privacy@canso.org](mailto:privacy@canso.org).

**Why do we process this personal data?**

CANSO and CANSO B.V. operate a wide variety of services and platforms for the benefit of CANSO Members, the broader aviation community, regulators, governments and stakeholders and the general public. These include events, news reports, CANSO's Member extranet 'Global ATM Net', CANSO CRM (Customer Relationship Management) system, CANSO website, CANSO mailing systems, World ATM Congress, trainings and others.

In accordance with our legal and ethical obligations, we strive to minimise the personal data we collect and use about you to those required for the specific service.

Nonetheless, we may need to collect and process your personal data when you:

  * Navigate our services in order to personalise your experience based on your declared preferences or pricing segments
  * Register for a product or service provided by CANSO or CANSO B.V. in order to ensure the right products/services are delivered to you in accordance with your selections and preferences
  * Make a purchase on any of our platforms in order to complete the transaction
  * Respond to or participate in a survey, contest, or a marketing communication in order to inform you about our activities, the results
  * Make a customer service request or submit a complaint in the context of our disciplinary process

**Services relating to our membership offer and our approach to protecting your privacy**

Most of our services form an integral part of our membership offer, an agreement between CANSO and its Members. We collect and process personal data in order to fulfill the obligations that result from this agreement.

Our membership offer enables our Members to benefit from facilitated networking (via events, online platforms, Member listings, and online discussion platforms etc.) and access to exclusive content produced by CANSO and its Members. We therefore collect personal details in order to deliver these subscribed services and to personalise a Member's experience.

For example, on our Global ATM-net (a service for our Members only) a detailed CANSO membership list is available for our membership as part of our membership subscription service. This list includes the Focal Point contact details per Member organisation. Under the conditions for access/use, it is stated that under no circumstances are Members allowed to share any data with Third Parties, meaning non-Members. CANSO also publishes a public list of its Members on its public website, in order to enable business partners and the general public to confirm membership status.

Inactive person and membership records will be accumulated in our archive, which contains primary source documents that have been accumulated over the course of the organisation's lifetime, and is kept to show, when required, the function and historic activities of persons or organisations for future generations. The archive is only accessible for a small group of pre-authorised CANSO and CANSO BV staff.

**Working processes**

In order to be able to facilitate a membership subscription and run the CANSO work programme effectively (this includes our standing committees, global and regional workgroups and taskforces), CANSO Member details such as name and email addresses, are shared within each group or work structure (including CANSO and CANSO B.V. staff, secondees and contractors and CANSO Members). These recipients, who may be located outside the European Union, are authorised to do so under explicit data protection agreements held between these individuals and CANSO and/or CANSO B.V.

**Marketing communications**

CANSO and CANSO B.V. regularly send out newsletters containing information about upcoming activities and events, industry news and updates, and special offers for which you may qualify. For you to receive these newsletters, we collect and process your personal details to ensure they reach you and that we filter content that does not interest you.

These communications form an integral part of the membership offer and are therefore communicated in the context of CANSO membership. However, we also target marketing communications to non-members individuals who have opted in for our communications with consent (via an online subscription form on our website). We do not send marketing communications to individuals who have not requested it.

**Event services**

CANSO endeavours to facilitate the best event registration and participation experience possible and accordingly works with partners and sponsors to:

  * Disseminate knowledge and content
  * Participate and contribute to discussions and surveys through platforms such as LinkedIn, Twitter, Monkey Survey, Sendsteps or similar third-party platforms
  * Provide you with relevant and related marketing messages and special offers through platforms such as Mailchimp, Drupal, LinkedIn, Twitter or similar third-party platforms
  * Connect you with other event delegates and industry representatives through dissemination of participant details
  * Share event reports and recordings, which may include presentations, video, photography and audio recordings, survey results and participant details
  * Share personal data with suppliers and partners if this is required to execute their services, such as: support in visa applications, hotel bookings, process of event fee payments, participation in cultural programmes and side events and related logistic purposes.

Event attendees benefit from these services when complying with the terms and conditions upon registration.

To this end, CANSO may collect, process and archive the personal data as listed under "What personal data do we process?" of event participants (delegates, speakers, presenters, exhibitors and sponsors) and if applicable participating spouses and/or relatives.

**Content services**

CANSO and CANSO B.V. aim to provide a wide array of content-driven services which allow users to gain new knowledge and insights on a wide variety of topics.

Some of the content shared is provided by sponsoring organisations or business partners who provide you with the content in exchange for your contact details in order to provide you further relevant marketing information.

**Who do we share your personal data with?**

In order to deliver our services, we may sometimes partner with third-parties in order to deliver the best experience possible for you. These partners, in and outside the European Union, are contractually bound with us in order to ensure that your personal data benefits from the same levels of protection as they have when handled directly by CANSO or CANSO B.V.

**For how long do we retain the data?**

In accordance with the GDPR, CANSO and CANSO B.V. retain your personal details for as long as is necessary for the initial purpose for which it was collected. There also may be statutory retention periods as prescribed by (Dutch) law. As a result, depending on the service you use, or the applicable law we may retain your data for differing periods of time.

**Use of cookies**

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your computer browser from a website's computer and is stored on your computer, if your browser's preferences allow it. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access its own cookies, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

CANSO may use cookies to help the server identify you when you log in to secure areas of the site, such as Global ATM-net. The cookies store your login information, so you can enter and leave the website without having to re-enter the same information over and over.

We also use cookies to track online traffic flow through Google Analytics. This service, offered by Google, analyses activity on the website. For these purposes, Google collects anonymous information related to web traffic and the number of visitors. This tool allows CANSO to measure the performance of the website in terms of browsing and to consolidate activity reports and other services. In addition, some third party content on the website (advertisements and embedded PDFs) use cookies to track online traffic.

You have the opportunity to set your web browser to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. Information supplied by cookies can help CANSO provide you with a better user experience. Please note that not accepting cookies may affect your ability to access certain parts of our website.

**Security**

CANSO has taken adequate measures to ensure that the servers hosting the processed personal data prevent, to the extent possible:

  * The processing, access or unauthorised modification of such data
  * The inadequate use or disclosure of such data
  * The unlawful destruction or accidental loss of such data

In this respect, CANSO and CANSO B.V. employees who have access to these data are subject to a strict confidentiality obligation. CANSO and CANSO B.V. cannot, however, be held liable for any misappropriation of these data by a third party in spite of the adopted security measures.

The users undertake not to commit any acts which may be contrary to the present Privacy Policy, the Terms of use for the website or, generally, the law. Offences against the confidentiality, integrity and availability of computer systems and saved data, processed or transmitted by such systems, or the attempt to commit any of these offenses, are punishable by imprisonment and/or by a financial penalty.

**Your rights**

You may at any time request access, rectification or, if necessary, deletion to/ from personal data, with the exception of those which CANSO would have a legal obligation to keep, by sending a written request (if applicable: accompanied by a valid proof of ID) to the data controller:

  * At the following postal address: CANSO / Database Administration, Polarisavenue 85-e, 2132 JH Hoofddorp, The Netherlands or

  * To the following email address: privacy@canso.org

CANSO will then take the necessary measures to satisfy this request as soon as possible.

**Note concerning minors**

Persons under the age of 18 and persons who do not have full legal capacity are not permitted to communicate their personal data to CANSO.

**Applicable Law**

This Privacy Policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the law of the Netherlands, and based on the GDPR. All disputes arising out of or in connection with this Privacy Policy must be dealt with under the jurisdiction of the courts of the Netherlands.

**Amendments**

CANSO and CANSO B.V. reserve the right to change any of the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time and without notice. CANSO and CANSO B.V. therefore recommends that you review this Privacy Policy from time to time, or before making a transaction.

Last updated Hoofddorp 24 May 2018

#### Attachments
